Power can be murder to resist.
The Firm is a drama, mystery, thriller film directed by Sydney Pollack.
Mitch McDeere is a young man with a promising future in Law.
About to sit his Bar exam, he is approached by 'The
Firm' and made an offer he doesn't refuse.
Seduced by the money and gifts showered on him, he is totally
oblivious to the more sinister side of his company.
Then, two Associates are murdered.
The FBI contact him, asking him for information and suddenly his life is ruined.
He has a choice - work with the FBI, or stay with the Firm.
Either way he will lose his life as he knows it.
Mitch figures the only way out is to follow his own plan...
Mitch McDeere, played by Tom Cruise.
Abby McDeere, played by Jeanne Tripplehorn.
Avery Tolar, played by Gene Hackman.
Oliver Lambert, played by Hal Holbrook.
Lamar Quinn, played by Terry Kinney.
William Devasher, played by Wilford Brimley.
The Firm is a 1993 American legal thriller film directed by Sydney Pollack, and starring Tom Cruise, Jeanne
Tripplehorn, Gene Hackman, Ed Harris, Holly Hunter, Hal Holbrook, David Strathairn and Gary Busey.
The film is based on the 1991 novel of the same name by author John Grisham.
Released on June 30, 1993, the film was a major commercial success, grossing $270.2 million against a budget of $42 million, making it the highest-grossing film adapted from a Grisham novel, fifth highest-grossing
and the highest-grossing R-rated film of 1993, and received generally positive reviews for the performances (particularly from Cruise and Hunter), although the screenplay received some criticism.
Holly Hunter was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Supporting
Actress, while Dave Grusin was nominated for Best Original Score.
The film explores themes of blackmail, married couple,
fbi, cayman islands, memphis, tennessee.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.